Newton Diehl Baker Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- General Correspondence, 1922-1937 (Box 16-243)
  - National Peace Conference
    - 1936-1937
    - 1937 (Box 175)
  - National Relief Committee
    - 1934-1937
  - National Relief Work (Alan Burns), 1935
  - National Society of Penal Information, 1929-1931 (Box 176)
  - National World Court Committee, 1931-1935
  - New York County Lawyers Association, 1931-1934
  - New York Times, letter, 11 Nov. 1935
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1927-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 177)
  - "No-Nz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1936
    - 1937 (Box 178)
  - "O" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 179)
  - Ohio Bar Association, 1928-1931
  - Ohio State University, Columbus, Ohio
    - 1932
    - 1933-1935 (Box 180)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 181)
    - Industrial Research, 1935
    - Military training
      - 1934
      - 1935 (Box 182)
  - "Pa-Ph" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1929
    - 1930-1934 (Box 183)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 184)
  - Palmer, Frederick D.
    - 1930-1935
    - Comments and acknowledgments on Newton D. Baker: America at War, by Palmer, 1931 (Box 185)
  - Park School of Cleveland, Cleveland, Ohio, 1933
  - Peabody, George Foster
    - 1922-1929
    - 1930-1935 (Box 186)
  - Permanent Court of Arbitration, Hague Tribunal, Netherlands
    - 1928-1930
    - 1930, 1935-1936 (Box 187)
  - Pershing, John J.
    - National Military Park Association, 1931
    - Memoirs, 1931
  - Phi Gamma Delta
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1935 (Box 188)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 189)
  - Photographs
    - 1929-1931
    - 1932 (Box 190)
  - "Pi-Pq" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 191)
  - "Pr-Pz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 192)
  - Presidential campaign, 1932
  - President's Organization on Unemployment Relief
    - 1931
    - 1931-1932 (Box 193)
  - Progress and the Constitution, 1923
  - Prohibition report, 1931
  - "Q" miscellaneous
    - 1924-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 194)
  - "Ra-Rh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 195)
  - Radio Corp. of America
    - 1933-1934
    - 1934-1936 (Box 196)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 197)
  - Religious Education Foundation
    - 1928-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 198)
  - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1931
  - "Ri-Rof" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 199)
  - "Rog-Rz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1932 (Box 200)
    - 1932-1936 (Box 201)
    - 1937 (Box 202)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 1935-1936
  - Rotary Foundation, 1935
  - "Sa-Scg" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 203)
  - Sarah Lawrence College, Bronxville, N.Y., 1930-1935
  - "Sch-Sd" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1937 (Box 204)
  - Scott, Frank A., 1922-1937 (Box 205)
  - "Se-Shd" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1923
    - 1924-1937 (Box 206)
  - Security Owners Association, 1933-1935
  - Selzer, Louis B., 1930 (Box 207)
  - "She-Shz", 1922-1937
  - Shotwell, James Thomson, 1929-1937 (Box 208)
  - "Si-Sn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1933 (Box 209)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 210)
  - "So-Ss" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 211)
  - Social Science Research Council
    - 1932
    - Advisory Committee on International Relations, 1931
  - "Sta-Sth" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1930
    - 1931-1937 (Box 212)
  - Stevens Institute of Technology, Hoboken, N.J., Committee on Educational Finance, 1932
  - "Sti-Stz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1937 (Box 213)
  - Stocks, 1928
  - Stone Mountain Confederate Association, Stone Mountain, Ga.
    - 1927
    - 1928-1929 (Box 214)
  - "Su-Sz" miscellaneous
    - 1923-1936
    - 1937 (Box 215)
  - Survey Associates, 1930-1936
  - "Ta-Tn" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1928
    - 1929-1936 (Box 216)
    - 1937 (Box 217)
  - "To-Tz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1936
    - 1937 (Box 218)
  - Town Hall Club of New York, 1935-1937
  - Tuskegee Normal and Industrial Institute, Tuskegee, Ala., 1937
  - Twentieth Century Fund
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1931 (Box 219)
    - 1931-1934 (Box 220)
    - 1934-1936 (Box 221)
    - Reports for annual meeting, 1927 (Box 222)
  - "U" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1937
  - Ungerleider, Samuel, 1929-1935
  - United Educational Program, 1932
  - United States Attorney General, Department of State (Box 223)
  - United States Chamber of Commerce, 1930
  - United States Society
    - 1932-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 224)
  - "V" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1937 (Box 225)
  - Van Sweringen, O. P. and M. J., 1929-1931
  - Vaness Co., 1927-1928
  - Vinson, Robert E., 1934 (Box 226)
  - "Wa-Wd" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1932
    - 1933-1937 (Box 227)
  - War Policies Commission, 1931
  - Washington and Lee University, Lexington, Va.
    - 1928-1931
    - 1932-1937 (Box 228)
  - "We-Wg" miscellaneous
    - 1922
    - 1922-1931 (Box 229)
    - 1932-1937 (Box 230)
  - Welfare Federation
    - 1927
    - 1928-1933 (Box 231)
  - Western Reserve University, Cleveland, Ohio
    - 1923-1927
    - 1927-1934 (Box 232)
    - 1935-1937 (Box 233)
    - Request Committee
    - School of Applied Social Sciences, Group Work Committee, 1929-1930
    - University Neighborhood Centers, 1929
  - "Wh" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 234)
  - Wheeling & Lake Erie Railroad, 1927-1928
  - "Wia-Wil" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1927
    - 1928-1933 (Box 235)
    - 1934-1937 (Box 236)
  - Wickersham, George W., 1929-1935
  - Wilkins, Ernest H., 1929
  - Willard, Daniel
    - 1929-1934
    - 1935-1937 (Box 237)
  - Williamsburg, Va., speech, 1934
  - "Wim-Wn" miscellaneous
    - 1923-1936
    - 1937 (Box 238)
  - "Wo-Wz" miscellaneous
    - 1922-1933
    - 1934-1937 (Box 239)
  - Wilson, Edith Bolling Galt, 1929-1933
  - Woodrow Wilson Foundation
    - 1926-1929
    - 1929-1933 (Box 240)
  - Woodrow Wilson Memorial, speech, 1932
  - Woodrow Wilson Memorial Society, 1929-1933
  - World Peace Foundation
    - 1932-1933
    - 1933-1935 (Box 241)
    - 1936-1937 (Box 242)
    - Cooperation of peace agencies, 1935
  - Wright, Fulton and Peggy Baker, 1930-1937
  - Wright, Howell, 1929-1930
  - "X-Z" miscellaneous
    - 1923-1928
    - 1929-1937 (Box 243)
  - Young, Hugh H., 1929-1932
  - Young Democratic Clubs of America, 1932-1935
  - "Z" miscellaneous, 1929-1937
- Speeches and Writings, 1915-1937 (Box 244-252)
  Correspondence, notes, drafts, printed matter, and miscellaneous material relating to speeches and writings by Baker.
  Arranged by type of writing and speeches organized chronologically therein.
  - Speeches (Box 244)
    - 1915-1918
    - 1919-1922 (Box 245)
    - 1923-1926 (Box 246)
    - 1927-1931 (Box 247)
    - 1931-1932 (Box 248)
    - 1933-1935 (Box 249)
    - 1935-1937, undated (Box 250)
    - Miscellaneous, 1918-1919, 1932 (Box 251)
  - Writings
    - Why We Went to War, draft, notes, and related matter, 1936
    - "Cancellation of War Debts," public response to article, A-Z, 1926-1927 (Box 252)
- Miscellany, 1918-1935 (Box 253-254)
  Miscellaneous topical files.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of organization, subject, or title of writing.
  - John Hopkins University, Baltimore, Md., Presidential Committee, master file and notes, 1934-1935 (Box 253)
  - "Report of General T. H. Bliss on the Supreme War Council," 1918
  - Senate investigation (Chamberlain), congratulations on Baker's reply to committee, A-Z, 1918 (Box 254)
  - Your Hall of Fame, by Robert Underwood Johnson, 1935
- Ralph Hayes File, 1916-1962 (Box 255-265)
  Correspondence between Baker and Ralph Hayes, subject files, speeches and writings, and printed matter.
  Arranged by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Correspondence (Box 255)
    - Baker and Ralph Hays
      - 1916-1924, (12 folders)
      - 1925-1927, (12 folders) (Box 256)
      - 1928-1929, (24 folders) (Box 257)
      - 1930-Mar. 1932, (27 folders) (Box 258)
      - Apr.-Dec. 1932, (12 folders) (Box 259)
      - 1933-1934, (24 folders) (Box 260)
      - 1935-1949, (44 folders) (Box 261)
    - Pauer, Lewis, 1962
  - Subject file
    - Baker, Newton D.
      - Funeral, 1937-1938
      - Memorial meeting, 1943-1944
    - Encyclopedia Britannica, May 1922-1945, undated, (22 folders) (Box 262)
    - Replies to speech, Institute of Politics, Williamstown, Mass., July-Sept. 1931, (3 folders)
    - Sugar processing tax, 1933-1934
  - Speeches, articles and clippings, 1918-1945, (9 folders) (Box 263)
  - Miscellaneous printed matter (Box 264)
    - Jan.-Mar. 1932
    - Appointment to Permanent Court of Arbitration, Hague Tribunal, Netherlands, 1928 (Box 265)
    - Cleveland contempt case, 1929
    - General, 1928-1937
- Letterbooks, 1896-1917 (Box 266-275, Reel 1-18)
  Bound volumes of copies of personal letters sent, 1896-1916, and of letters sent as secretary of war, 1916-1917.
  Arranged chronologically.
  Available on microfilm. Shelf no. 18,549
  - Personal (Box 266, Reel 1)
    - 30 July 1896-20 Mar. 1905
    - 22 Mar. 1905-21 July 1906 (Reel 2)
    - 13 July 1906-22 Jan. 1908 (Box 267, Reel 3)
    - 23 Jan. 1908-14 Jan. 1909 (Reel 4)
    - 14 Jan. 1909-9 Mar. 1910 (Box 268, Reel 5)
    - 9 Mar.-22 Dec. 1910 (Reel 6)
    - 22 Dec. 1910-22 Sept. 1911 (Box 269, Reel 7)
    - 22 Sept. 1911-2 Apr. 1912 (Reel 8)
    - 2 Apr.-29 Aug. 1912 (Box 270, Reel 9)
    - 29 Aug. 1912-6 Feb. 1913 (Reel 10)
    - 6 Feb.-10 July 1913 (Box 271, Reel 11)
    - 11 July-1 Dec. 1913 (Reel 12)
    - 2 Dec. 1913-20 Aug. 1914 (Box 272, Reel 13)
    - 21 Aug. 1914-8 Apr. 1915 (Reel 14)
    - 8 Apr.-31 Dec. 1915 (Box 273, Reel 15)
    - 9 Mar.-10 May 1916 (Reel 17)
  - Secretary of war (Box 274, Reel 16)
    - 10 May-13 July 1916
    - 13 July-25 Sept. 1916
    - 23 Sept.-5 Dec. 1916 (Box 274, Reel 18)
    - 4-20 Dec. 1916 (Box 275, Reel 18)
  - Secretary of war, presidential
    - 10 Mar. 1916-10 Apr. 1917
- Addition, 1917-1930 (Box 275)
  Letters to D. C. Westenhaver and Paul Westenhaver.
  - Letters to D. C. Westenhaven and Paul Westenhaven, 1917-1930, (2 folders) (Box 275)